[Forging Justice]
[Episode 30]
To be honest,
this is too huge a price
to pay
just for Yan Jicai.
I'm not only doing this for him,
but also for legal justice,
for my mentor,
and for Yan Jicai's wife
and daughter.
I know
if things get out of hand,
you'll be caught in a dilemma.
I'll be fine.
I'm just worried about you.
How about...
How about we get a divorce?
[Meeting Room 1]
Hello, Judge Xia.
I'm Hu Xudong's defense lawyer,
Chen Yizhong.
This is my business card,
my license to practice law,
the letter of introduction
from my law firm,
and the Defense Authorization Letter.
Please take a look.
Hello, Mr. Chen.
My name is Xia Yingjie.
I'm the judge for this case.
Judge Xia,
I'm here to apply to review the files,
especially those issued
by the public security bureau
after the supplementary investigation.
Your application is received.
We'll arrange for it soon.
Judge Xia, may I ask
if there's any new evidence?
According to regulations,
defense lawyers
can only review and copy certain files.
You see,
there are still many doubts
about this case.
Besides,
the chain of evidence is incomplete.
I deem it unfair
to my client
if I can't access
all the evidence.
Plus, the new procedure law
clearly stipulates
According to the Decision on Revising
the Criminal Procedure Law of PRC
that lawyers have the right
approved in the 4th session
of the 8th National People's Congress,
to review, copy,
the new Criminal Procedure Law
finished amendment on March 17, 1996,
and was enacted on January 1, 1997.
and request to verify evidence.
Mr. Chen,
no need to recite the legal articles.
We won't deliberately give you a hard time
or any special treatment.
Everything will follow
the new procedure law.
As for anything unclear
about the articles,
the court now has the right
of interpretation.
Okay.
How long have you been waiting?
I just arrived.
A joint meeting of the three chiefs.
What a headache.
Hu Xudong's case has dragged on
for so long.
We're under tremendous public pressure.
Today's meeting was exactly about that.
It's not that we're holding it up.
The procuratorate returned the file first,
asking for a supplementary investigation.
But in the end,
it still falls on us, doesn't it?
Anyway, I don't feel great about it.
Don't worry. I'll try the case myself.
Have you read the file?
Yes.
Your hunch was right.
What?
Is the evidence that weak?
It depends on how you look at it.
Stop beating around the bush with me.
Just speak up.
The chain of evidence is incomplete.
The confession also shows flaws.
It's not a serious problem,
nor a trivial one.
Yu,
you lack confidence, don't you?
I just think
that Qian Xingliang's case incurred
too high a price.
The court can't go through it again.
I doubt if that'll happen.
At least this time,
the victim was dead and buried.
He wouldn't come back alive
like Yu Sanhua did.
In short,
make it quick.
Try the case and end it fast.
Just make sure you handle the facts
and evidence properly.
Now that I'm the presiding judge,
I'll ensure the case is rock-solid
and stands to scrutiny,
both now and in the future.
All I want to know
is what exactly
happened that day.
Have you asked Lyu Siyi?
She said she never touched that mat.
And you believe her just because
she's your daughter?
I didn't touch that mat.
And I didn't snitch either.
What if your daughter is the one lying?
What will you do then?
Captain Lyu.
How did you get in here?
The door was open.
I talked to Wang Danni.
What did she say?
"Go away."
No, no!
She told me to go away.
Has it ever crossed your mind
that this is just a misunderstanding?
Wang Danni didn't lie.
Your daughter was indeed wronged.
If that's really the case,
this burden can be lifted
from their hearts for good.
From yours, too.
Your daughter
refuses to talk to you, doesn't she?
Just like her, I also
hate talking to my dad.
Perhaps she'll be
willing to tell me something.
[Delivery Room]
Ding Rui's family?
Here I am.
How's it going?
She gave birth to a girl
who weighs 3.35 kg. They're both fine.
They're both fine now, right?
Yes.
Honey, I'm proud of you!
Honey, I love you!
Sir, sir.
Sorry for that.
We got it.
Dad.
Keep it down.
Dad, they're both fine.
Dad, I'm a father now too.
You're a father now.
And you're a grandfather.
This is marvelous.
Now I have two sweethearts.
Wh-When can we get in there?
May I go in?
-Come on.
-Congratulations.
Congrats, Mr. Lu. Come on.
-Cheers.
-Congratulations.
-Such good news.
I'll down it.
He really did.
What a good drinker you are, Mr. Lu.
-Bravo!
-You can really hold your liquor.
You're so different now that you have
a daughter.
Of course!
I'm telling you,
right now,
I look down on all of you.
I contempt you in every way.
You're a bunch of stinky men!
I also have a daughter.
Listen,
the worst is yet to come.
Little girls can be quite a challenge!
Challenge?
I'd love that!
I'd love that.
Come on.
Cheers.
-Come on.
-What about you?
Won't you make some plans?
I'll take what fate gives me.
If it's meant to be, it will be.
Everyone, please quiet down.
I have some good news to announce.
It's...
about me.
I have
officially taken office
as Guangdong Dingxin Trading Group's
chief legal advisor in this province.
I'll be working
in Nanyun Building in Nanlu.
If you ever visit the provincial capital,
come have tea with me.
You're welcome anytime.
Easy on it.
You're always welcome anytime.
Come on!
Qin,
congratulations.
Guys, get up now.
Come on.
Good things come in pairs, right?
Guys, let's toast to Qin.
Sure thing.
One more sip, guys.
Let's do.
Qin, you must take a big sip.
-Okay.
-Sure.
What happened?
He met a big shot.
Zeming.
Mr. Li and I parted ways
on amicable terms.
Mr. Li and the law firm
treated me quite well
in the past years.
Li Xiang.
Thank you.
Let's have a drink.
Sure.
Come on!
Sure. Let's do.
Count me in as well.
Come on.
Cheers, the three of us.
Congrats, Qin.
Thanks.
Whose phone is ringing?
Is it yours?
How am I able to afford a phone?
Then...
Sorry, I need to take this.
Hello?
Hey, Ms. Gui.
Yes, yes.
I'll report for duty
the day after tomorrow.
I've found an apartment.
Two bedrooms and one living room.
Thank you for your concern, Ms. Gui.
Thanks a lot.
See you the day after tomorrow then.
Sure. Okay.
Goodbye.
The company insisted on
providing me with a phone,
saying the fees would be reimbursed.
-Great.
-Good for you.
Mr. Qin.
What
brand is it?
A huge brand.
That phone costs over ten grand.
Ten grand?
No, no.
The brand
is called Svoboda.
S-S...
What?
Svoboda.
Come on, guys.
A toast to Svoboda.
Sure. Svoboda.
Why are you eating that, Diandian?
Didn't I tell you to go find Tongtong
at Uncle Yin's?
Tongtong got sick.
Uncle Yin had to take her to the hospital,
so he sent me home first.
This is not a proper meal, you know?
Your stomach will be upset
if you eat too much of this.
What would you like to have?
Noodles, alright?
With an egg?
Wait a moment then.
Stop watching TV.
Read a book instead.
Come on.
Okay.
I'll let you know when the food's ready.
Dinner's ready, Diandian.
Diandian.
Dad, Dad!
Is this you?
Yes.
It's me when I was young.
What about this lady?
Is it Mom when she was young?
No, it's not your mom.
Your mom looked exactly
like you when she was young.
What a big egg.
It's hot.
It's me.
You have the supplementary materials
from the procuratorate, right?
Place them on my desk tomorrow.
I'll take a look.
[Beijing O&M Advertising Co., Ltd.]
Qiuyue.
Why are you eating leftovers again?
Look at you, overweight.
It's caused by your eating habits.
You haven't spoken
a proper sentence to me for over a month.
You're leaving tomorrow.
Why don't you say a few more words?
Scold me if you want.
It'll make me feel better.
Qin!
If I had agreed
to divorce you back then,
would you be living
a better life now?
I...
I apologize to you.
I reflect upon my wrongdoing.
I promise to treat you well from now on.
Can you please not see
that female boss again?
Svoboda.
Did I allow you to touch my things?
Are you illiterate or what?
All messed up, huh?
Leave them there.
I'll tidy them up for you later.
Speak up.
I agree with Court Pre. Yu.
The death penalty is a fitting sentence.
The evidence is conclusive,
and the facts are clear.
Xia Yingjie, why are you so quiet?
Don't you always speak your mind?
I'm gathering my thoughts.
Isn't it even necessary?
Court Pre. Yu is highly professional.
He can pick up on what's not being said.
Just say it if you disagree.
Fine, I'll be straightforward then.
There are quite many doubts.
I'll start with the major aspects
before we get into details.
First,
the motive.
It's unreasonable
and far-fetched.
Second, the murder weapon.
It was not at the scene,
not thrown away or buried,
but taken home.
This is odd.
Third,
the origins of the bloodstains
on the clothes are questionable.
Fourth,
the time of the crime.
Hu can neither be established guilty,
nor ruled out as a suspect.
Fifth, the confessions.
They are the most problematic.
Obviously, Hu was exhausted
on purpose when being interrogated.
According to the transcripts,
the first interview
lasted for 11 hours.
After a half-hour break,
it continued for another 11 hours.
It went on and on.
Even a man of iron couldn't take it.
Besides,
there are three confessions in total.
Hu denied doing the crime initially.
The second and third confessions
show gradual alignment with the facts.
He was probably induced to them,
or he was just too tired.
Then do you think
it is likely for the defendant
to retract his confessions in court?
It's possible.
It depends on
what the defender opts for.
Then just make
the defender give up on it.
I brought a can of tea from the car.
Make some nice tea for them later.
Okay.
What time is the appointment?
In ten minutes.
Okay.
I'll be on watch
at the door later.
On watch?
This is not a spy mission.
What's that for?
You're making me nervous.
Safety first, right?
Lihui.
Can you not bring divorce again
without careful consideration?
Not even when we argue,
unless you truly want a divorce.
Sorry.
I was just afraid...
I don't fear being implicated.
At worst, we can always go sell
rice noodles somewhere else.
I'll take Guiya as my teacher
and learn the craft from her.
You'll be spared from labor.
Collecting payment
will be your only job.
Okay, I'll remember that.
Easy with the talk later.
Don't say anything you shouldn't say.
What are you talking about? I...
You think your wife is that stupid?
For what it's worth, I'm a Doctor of Law.
Alright.
I'll stand guard for you then, Dr. Zhang.
What did you mean by that?
Why did you say
"make the defender give up on it"?
Have you seen the supplementary evidence?
Yes.
Many questions
still remain unanswered.
I'm trying to say
that the glove alone
can prove Hu Xudong to be guilty.
There is indeed blood on it,
but the blood type can't be identified.
How can you be so sure that it's his?
There are bloodstains.
And it was found
near the crime scene.
It is also identical to the one
at Hu's home.
They fit them perfectly well.
All these coincidences
are now gathered.
What are your true thoughts?
My true thoughts don't matter.
What matters is the evidence.
From the very beginning,
the police have determined
that Hu Xudong committed the crime.
It's a typical act of deriving evidence
from confessions.
So what?
How else to solve the case?
Yu Gaoyuan.
You've changed quite a lot
over these years.
Court Pres. Qiu.
Finished lunch?
Is he well-suited to handle
Hu Xudong's case?
There had better be no slips.
Should it be handled by you, if not him?
I'd really love to contribute
to the court.
But I'm about to attend training
at the Party School, right?
I just don't have time for this case.
That being said,
I'll absolutely follow
the organization's arrangements.
If he's recommended
for training at the Party School,
I'll be fully supportive.
You think he'd be interested?
I heard that he has recently
sent an application
to the Advanced Training Center for Judges
in Beijing.
He's been actively in touch with
the Supreme Court.
I guess before long,
he'll become our leader.
I see.
No wonder
when I went to
his office a few days ago,
he was reading English newspapers
and memorizing vocabulary.
A small temple
is no place for a great Buddha.
His eyes
are set on Beijing.
Why would he
care for this tiny
Binjiang Intermediate Court?
Room 1112.
This way, right?
Zhou Tong.
Please come in.
Have some tea.
Thank you.
Here you are.
Zhang,
he is who I told you about,
a senior to me.
I guarantee that he is absolutely
trustworthy.
Hello, my name is Zhang Lihui.
I used to be
the resident prosecutor of Bieshan Prison.
I'm Zeng Qiang,
a reporter for the Weekly.
Thank you for coming today.
I'm a loyal reader of your paper.
Thanks.
Although
the Weekly is just a local media outlet,
it does have some influence
nationwide.
I think it perfectly meets
your demands.
Let's cut to the chase then.
I hope the article can be
as objective as possible.
It shouldn't incite emotions,
distort or cherry-pick facts,
or take things out of context.
It must not attack the socialist system,
the Party's leadership,
the judicial system
or China's rule of law.
All I am trying to do is
draw the attention
of relevant departments.
There's another thing.
When the draft is completed,
may I take a look at it first?
Yes, of course.
You're even qualified
to be our editor-in-chief.
Zhang, it's a compliment for you.
The words just
came out weirdly.
D-Did I put my foot
in my mouth again?
No, no.
I...
I'm really sorry, Prosecutor Zhang.
You see,
I completely understand
why you are anxious and stressed.
So...
I'm not anxious or stressed.
I just hope the article
can be published soon.
Or it will be too late.
Okay, let's not waste any time then.
The recording will only serve
as a reference for my article.
It won't be leaked to a third party.
Is that okay?
Yes.
Shall we begin?
Am I going to be executed?
I think we stand
a higher chance if we fight for
a suspended death penalty.
Still a suspended death penalty?
Yes.
First offense of casual nature.
A killing in the heat of passion.
You admitted guilt with a good attitude
and actively offered compensate.
These are grounds
for a suspended death penalty.
Just tell me straight.
If...
I don't get executed,
how many years will I have to serve?
About 20 years.
Twenty years.
By the time I am released,
I'll be about the same age
as my dad is now.
Hu Xudong.
I can and I am
willing to plead
not guilty for you.
What do you think?
Let's go for it.
Had better get over with it.
I'm ready to take the risk.
What's the case?
Paraquat poisoning.
Please let us through.
How much did she take in?
Not much, allegedly.
When did it happen?
Last night at 11...
Gastric lavage with 2% sodium bicarbonate.
Got it.
Hurry, 5,000 milliliters first.
Where did you buy the pesticide?
The c-county agricultural supply
corporation's
retail store near the city gate.
Just the one next to
the long-distance coach station.
When did you buy it?
The day before yesterday.
I bought it when I got off
the bus from Nanlu.
Why did you buy pesticide?
Because I wanted to die.
Okay. Sure.
Come find me
at Nanyun Building if you need anything.
Good. Okay.
Alright, let's talk when we meet up.
What is it with you?
This...
This one's the same.
Ms. Gui!
Do not come in.
Let's talk outside.
Outside.
Okay.
Ms. Gui,
are you alright?
This is all my fault.
What are you talking about?
You don't know?
I don't know.
Anyway,
please forgive me.
Due to
unforeseen circumstances,
my company has to terminate your contract.
So...
But you'll still receive
this month's salary,
in cash.
No tax needed.
Just take it.
But the phone I gave you earlier
is company property.
Please return it.
Thanks a lot.
Let's keep in touch.
Actually, let's not.
Ms. Gui!
Why is this happening?
I'm running a business here.
I don't want any trouble.
Sorry for everything.
Ms. Gui!
Ms. Gui,
it's fine that you sacked me,
but you should at least
tell me the reason, right?
Your wife came stir up trouble yesterday.
Do you really not know that?
She spewed tons of nonsense.
Anyway, she just hates
you working here.
She not only smashed
the door of the company,
but also scratched my face.
She's insane.
Take her to the doctor already!
I'm terribly sorry, Ms. Gui.
I swear to you—
I swear to you on my life
that she won't cause trouble here again!
She also drank pesticide.
A big bottle of it.
Everyone was terrified.
I immediately called an ambulance.
Then, she just ran off.
Is she okay?
She drank Paraquat,
didn't she?
How would I know what the hell she drank?
That was just a bluff.
She was faking it.
I promise that she will
absolutely never come here again.
-I guarantee that with my life.
-Mr. Qin,
I'm a businesswoman.
I'd rather stay out of such trouble.
That's all.
Crazy woman.
Why does your wife carry
fake pesticide with her all the time?
She often quarrels with others,
makes a scene,
and scares them.
Did you buy a bottle of real pesticide
to swap with hers?
I meant to drink it myself
right in front of her.
Then how did it end up
being taken by her?
Did you force it down her throat
or trick her into drinking it?
I'm fed up with this life!
You love playing dead, huh?
H-How could you do that?
You want to die, huh?
Fine.
You'll have to die today!
Will you drink this or not?
You won't, huh?
I will drink it if you don't!
I'll drink it!
Let me die!
Give it back to me!
How much pesticide did she take in?
I'm not sure about the exact amount.
Do you know how much
5 ml is?
Just this much.
And it's enough to kill.
I meant to drink it myself,
but she snatched it away.
She snatched it away?
Then why did you say you committed murder
when you turned yourself in?
I did commit murder.
Let me take you to the hospital.
So you still can't bear to leave me alone.
Let's make a good life together
from now on.
When Xiaowen is back,
let's start a wonderful new life together.
We will never part again.
So you waited
several hours
before sending her to the hospital,
right?
She threw up the pesticide,
and I proposed to take her
to the hospital.
But she said she was fine.
Little did I expect her condition
to worsen the next morning.
Prior to the purchase of the pesticide,
did you know about its toxicity
and the characteristics
of its onset?
No, not really.
Qin Zhigao.
You bought the pesticide.
She snatched it and drank it.
You don't know the amount she took in,
nor the toxicity of the drug.
Are you trying to tell me
that you turned yourself in out of guilt?
How is my wife now?
Has she pulled through?
Defendant,
do you have objections
to the alleged charges
in the indictment?
Yes, I do.
I didn't kill.
I'm innocent.
Is it your signature
on the confessions?
Yes.
Did anyone resort to
violence, like beatings,
to force you to sign them?
No.
No one interfered.
No one threatened you.
Then why did you sign the confessions
before reading through the transcripts?
At that time,
I hadn't slept for days.
I was not of sound mind.
I drank the pesticide myself.
It had nothing to do with Qin.
Please don't arrest him.
How is your relationship
with him?
Very good.
Qin and I are chummy.
Don't be fooled by others' nonsense.
Please don't arrest him.
Officers,
when can I be discharged
from the hospital?
I'd like to stay at home for recovery.
The doctor won't give me an exact time.
How long had you known Yin Ping,
the victim?
Ever since we were kids.
Then why did he
burn down your cowshed?
Because he went crazy.
I didn't provoke him anyway.
How did you deal with it?
First, I reported it to the police,
but they ignored it.
Then I went to the courthouse.
They said their hands were tied,
since he was a mental patient.
When all these departments
failed to
intervene with it,
did you consider revenge?
I was about to get married at that time.
How did I have time
to fight with a sick person?
Defendant,
half a year ago,
you were taken to the police station
due to a brawl, right?
Yes.
I brawled with a ticket conductor.
He asked me to buy a ticket.
I said I had bought one.
But he denied it.
He's laying a trap for Hu Xudong.
So I got into a fight with him.
You stated that you were drunk
at that time.
Is it true?
Yes.
How much did you drink?
I just got drunk.
I don't recall the amount.
Objection.
Presiding Judge,
the prosecutor's questions
are irrelevant to the case.
Prosecutor, limit your questions
to the case.
On the night
of October 17, 1996,
did you have any alcohol?
Yes, I did.
So, just like before,
you were drunk
and couldn't control yourself.
Is it correct?
That's only your opinion.
Objection!
Presiding Judge,
the prosecutor
is leading the defendant
with questions that are unrelated
to the case.
Prosecutor.
Presiding Judge,
we're trying to figure out the following.
First,
on the night of the incident,
did he or did he not...
What is the prosecutor trying to do?
Second,
did he lose control again...
It'll be fine.
And use violence?
Therefore, my questions just now
are not only relevant to the case,
but also of great importance.
The prosecutor cannot use
the fact that the defendant once
brawled with someone after drinking
to prove
that the defendant would commit
violent acts every time he drinks.
Pardon me for being blunt.
We can adopt
all available measures.
But she was brought in too late.
The window for resuscitation was missed.
There are slim chances of saving
her life.
I suggest you and your father discuss
whether to keep trying.
It will cost...
a great deal of money.
Defendant,
on the day of the incident,
as you left
Liu Erdong's place after drinking,
what were you wearing?
I had a shirt on the inside,
and a suit jacket on the outside.
Did you mention this suit jacket
to the police?
Why wasn't it noted down
in the confessions?
No one asked about that.
They spent
all the effort studying my shirt.
Where is the suit jacket now?
It's hung at home.
Presiding Judge,
we request the immediate retrieval
of the suit jacket
mentioned by the defendant
as new physical evidence,
and a test on it for bloodstains.
Noted by the court.
Defendant,
on the night of October 17th,
when you left
Liu Erdong's place
for home,
did you run into anyone
on the way?
No.
During the supplementary investigation
on November 19th,
this work glove was discovered
near the scene of crime.
There are bloodstains on it.
It's not written in the file.
I told you so.
They'd catch you off guard.
This newly discovered work glove
forms a pair with the one found
at the crime scene.
The defendant tried them on, and they fit.
Presiding Judge.
May I ask why
this physical evidence and statement
are not included
in the case file?
Prosecutor, how do you
explain this?
The evidence was newly obtained
as the police conducted
a supplementary investigation.
The time was so pressing
that we couldn't put it in the file.
Well then...
Presiding Judge,
the defense requests a short recess.
Recess granted.
Everyone, take a lunch break.
The court will resume at 2:00 p.m.
Let's go.
Go, Dad.
Move.
Xudong.
Xudong!
Just so you know,
we went to the hospital at noon.
How is she?
Still alive.
The hospital said she needs dialysis.
How is your relationship with her?
Terrible.
All my acquaintances know about her.
She's notorious.
Can you tell left from right?
These gloves fit either hands.
Do they fit?
Yes. Look.
Can you tell left from right?
These gloves work for both hands.
Just put them on.
Do they fit?
Yes.
This stuff fits nearly
every pair of hands.
Do they have front or back sides?
No, I guess not.
What's the point of that?
Defense, what are you trying to illustrate
with these
video materials?
The new physical evidence
provided by the prosecutor,
namely a work glove of this sort,
can be seen everywhere.
They're available
in several stores nearby.
And they are of the same type.
One size fits all.
Most importantly,
such work gloves
fit both hands.
That is to say,
even two randomly found
work gloves
can make a pair.
Defender, keep your remarks brief
during the evidence-review stage.
We are trying to say
that this physical evidence
has no direct connection to the case.
Besides, the crime scene is now
under construction.
This glove very likely belongs to
one of the workers.
We've investigated it.
The workers on the site do not
wear this kind of glove.
The possibility of it being
left there still cannot be ruled out.
On top of that, workers and villagers
pass by that dry ditch
all year round.
In addition,
is it really human blood
on that glove?
Is that blood from the defendant
or the victim?
The investigation authority has consulted
professional institutions.
The blood can only be confirmed
to be from humans.
The blood type cannot be identified.
That means it's not necessarily
Yin Ping's blood,
right?
Presiding Judge,
I request to ask the defendant
supplementary questions.
Request granted.
Defendant,
do you recognize this work glove?
No.
Every household
in the village
has gloves of sort for work.
Why would I recognize any?
Then why did the police
find only one glove
at your home?
Where is the other one?
Have you not lost a sock a before?
The defense rests.
Yes, yes.
Exactly.
This is also what I mean.
Just let him out for now.
If something truly
happens to his wife,
he won't be able to get away.
Okay, good.
Thanks, Fan.
Goodbye.
Kid...
Be seated.
Your father turned himself in.
The police have filed a case.
It's impossible to drop it
without proper cause.
That said,
the police can release him from detention
through bail.
We'll have to play it by ear then.
I'll arrange for you
to pick him up later.
Thank you, Uncle Ding.
Thank you so much.
We reenacted the scene on the site
where the crime happened.
On the night of the incident,
at about 11 p.m.,
in complete darkness,
it was nearly impossible to find
three shirt buttons in the pile of rocks
on the site
within a short time.
The moonlight is bright this season.
Visibility is high at night.
There are reports on the moon phase
and weather for the day.
On October 17th,
it was a crescent moon.
Only a quarter of the moon could be seen.
What's more,
the clouds were thick that night,
covering the moon.
There are no streetlights
within 300 meters of the scene.
Let me put it this way, everyone.
It was too dark to even see one's fingers.